<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>HBowie.net - From the Desk of H. Bowie</title>
    <link>https://hbowie.net/</link>
    <description>Stuff by Herb Bowie</description>
    <language>en</language>
	<item>
	  <title>Notenik 14.4.0 Released</title>
	  <link>https://hbowie.net/micro/notenik-14.4.0-released</link>
	  <guid>https://hbowie.net/micro/notenik-14.4.0-released</guid>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
	  <description>
	  	Notenik 14.4.0 is out, and is available for free from the Mac App Store. This release includes the following improvements: improved YAML parsing, for greater interoperability with Obsidian; a new option to sort a collection of notes by folder + seq + title; a new field type of page style, that can include special CSS to be applied to the display of a specific note; a new bulk edit option that can be used to modify several notes at once; a couple of bug fixes. 

	  </description>
	</item>
	<item>
	  <title>Some Hard Truths About Human Population Growth</title>
	  <link>https://hbowie.net/micro/some-hard-truths-about-human-population-growth</link>
	  <guid>https://hbowie.net/micro/some-hard-truths-about-human-population-growth</guid>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
	  <description>
	  	In 1800, the total human population on our planet was only 1 billion people. It took 127 years for that number to double to 2 billion. But then it took only 33 years to add the next billion. Since then, we’ve been adding another billion every 11 - 14 years, and doubling our population about every fifty years. At this point, in 2024, we now have in excess of 8 billion people on our planet – and we’re adding another quarter million every day.

	  </description>
	</item>
	<item>
	  <title>Notenik 14.3.0 Released</title>
	  <link>https://hbowie.net/micro/notenik-14.3.0-released</link>
	  <guid>https://hbowie.net/micro/notenik-14.3.0-released</guid>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
	  <description>
	  	Notenik 14.3.0 is out today in the Mac App Store, including support for sub-folders. Happy for great support from the Notenik Discourse community in beta testing this latest release. More info at [notenik.app.](https://notenik.app.) 

	  </description>
	</item>
	<item>
	  <title>Notenik 14.2.0 Released</title>
	  <link>https://hbowie.net/micro/notenik-14.2.0-released</link>
	  <guid>https://hbowie.net/micro/notenik-14.2.0-released</guid>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
	  <description>
	  	Version 14.2.0 of my open-source app Notenik is now available for free in the Mac App Store, with improved ability to show random, daily quotes from a commonplace book, as well as other improvements. 

	  </description>
	</item>
	<item>
	  <title>Notenik 14.1.0 Released</title>
	  <link>https://hbowie.net/micro/notenik-14.1.0-released</link>
	  <guid>https://hbowie.net/micro/notenik-14.1.0-released</guid>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
	  <description>
	  	Notenik 14.1.0 is out, and available for free from the Mac App Store. This release adds a duration field, and an export to iCal option, both of which are included in the rewrite of the guidance on [Using Notenik as a Travel Planner](https://notenik.app/kb/using-notenik-as-a-travel-planner.html). Notenik might be best described as a Personal Information Utility. 

	  </description>
	</item>
	<item>
	  <title>Notenik 14.0.0 Released</title>
	  <link>https://hbowie.net/micro/notenik-14.0.0-released</link>
	  <guid>https://hbowie.net/micro/notenik-14.0.0-released</guid>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
	  <description>
	  	Version 14.0.0 of my Mac app Notenik is out today, and available from the Mac App Store. A Notenik user recently posted a really good description of how Notenik differs from other (generally better-known) tools, and I suggest you [read that](https://discourse.notenik.app/t/why-notenik-vs-logseq-obsidian-or-devonthink/405/3?u=hbowie) if you&apos;re wondering what it is that makes Notenik special. 

	  </description>
	</item>
	<item>
	  <title>Reflections on the Christian Message</title>
	  <link>https://hbowie.net/micro/reflections-on-the-christian-message</link>
	  <guid>https://hbowie.net/micro/reflections-on-the-christian-message</guid>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
	  <description>
	  	When I think of the overarching message of Christ, three central concepts stand out for me.

	  </description>
	</item>
	<item>
	  <title>Notenik 13.5.0 Released</title>
	  <link>https://hbowie.net/micro/notenik-13.5.0-released</link>
	  <guid>https://hbowie.net/micro/notenik-13.5.0-released</guid>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
	  <description>
	  	Another new version of Notenik out today: 13.5.0! Free and open-source, available through the Mac App Store. 

Also, coincidentally, I received a lovely post this morning on the Notenik Discourse Forum from a user talking about how he was making use of the app, entitled &quot;[Thank you for producing great software](https://discourse.notenik.app/t/thank-you-for-producing-great-software/359).&quot;
	  </description>
	</item>
	<item>
	  <title>Notenik 13.4.0 Released</title>
	  <link>https://hbowie.net/micro/notenik-13.4.0-released</link>
	  <guid>https://hbowie.net/micro/notenik-13.4.0-released</guid>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
	  <description>
	  	Version 13.4.0 of Notenik (free and open source) is now available in the Mac App Store. Added &apos;Show in Finder&apos; for note files; added a script include command; improved the display of link fields.  

	  </description>
	</item>
	<item>
	  <title>They All Laughed</title>
	  <link>https://hbowie.net/micro/they-all-laughed</link>
	  <guid>https://hbowie.net/micro/they-all-laughed</guid>
	  <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
	  <description>
	  	Published a little appreciation for the Gershwin song, &quot;They All Laughed.&quot;

Available on [HBowie.net](https://hbowie.net/writings/they-all-laughed.html) and also at the [Lexicon of Song](https://lexiconofsong.org).
	  </description>
	</item>
  </channel>
</rss>
