<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Portable Wisdom</title>
  <subtitle>Daily Quotations from the desk of H. Bowie</subtitle>
  <link href="https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/feeds/atom.xml" type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://hbowie.net/" type="text/html" rel="alternate"  />
  <updated>2025-04-18T09:00:00Z</updated>
  <rights>Fair Use</rights>
  <author>
	<name>Various</name>
  </author>
  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/feeds/atom.xml</id>
	<entry>
	  <title>The US remains astonishingly backward when it comes to education</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/the-us-remains-astonishingly-backward-when-it-comes-to-education.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-18-the-us-remains-astonishingly-backward-when-it-comes-to-education.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-18T16:55:28Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-18T16:55:28Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Anu Partanen</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  It&apos;s an unfortunate fact that the United States remains astonishingly backward compared to almost all other advanced Western countries when it comes to education, because in America, what predicts how well a child will do in school is not a child&apos;s&#8230; 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>It&#8217;s an unfortunate fact that the United States remains astonishingly backward compared to almost all other advanced Western countries when it comes to education, because in America, what predicts how well a child will do in school is not a child&#8217;s aptitude or hard work, but the status of the child&#8217;s parents &#8211; which is to say, their own levels of education and wealth. Other countries suffer from this condition too, but the United States is especially anachronistic. And it&#8217;s getting worse: The influence of this wealth predictor in the United States today has only been growing stronger in recent years. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Anu Partanen,  the book <cite>The Nordic Theory of Everything: In Search of a Better Life</cite>, 2016</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Cultures as a kind of mental infection</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/cultures-as-a-kind-of-mental-infection.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-17-cultures-as-a-kind-of-mental-infection.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-17T16:16:38Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-17T16:16:38Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Yuval Noah Harari</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Ever more scholars see cultures as a kind of mental infection or parasite, with humans as its unwitting host. Organic parasites, such as viruses, live inside the body of their hosts. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Ever more scholars see cultures as a kind of mental infection or parasite, with humans as its unwitting host. Organic parasites, such as viruses, live inside the body of their hosts. They multiply and spread from one host to the other, feeding off their hosts, weakening them, and sometimes even killing them. As long as the hosts live long enough to pass along the parasite, it cares little about the condition of its host. In just this fashion, cultural ideas live inside the minds of humans. They multiply and spread from one host to another, occasionally weakening the hosts and sometimes even killing them. A cultural idea &#8211; such as belief in Christian heaven above the clouds or Communist paradise here on earth &#8211; can compel a human to dedicate his or her life to spreading that idea, even at the price of death. The human dies, but the idea spreads. According to this approach, cultures are not conspiracies concocted by some people in order to take advantage of others (as Marxists tend to think). Rather, cultures are mental parasites that emerge accidentally, and thereafter take advantage of all people infected by them. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Yuval Noah Harari,  the book <cite>Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind</cite>, 2015</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Technological Unemployment</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/technological-unemployment.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-16-technological-unemployment.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-16T16:05:19Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-16T16:05:19Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>John Maynard Keynes</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  We are being afflicted with a new disease of which some readers may not yet have heard the name, but of which they will hear a great deal in the years to come &#8211; namely, technological unemployment. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>We are being afflicted with a new disease of which some readers may not yet have heard the name, but of which they will hear a great deal in the years to come &#8211; namely, technological unemployment. This means unemployment due to our discovery of means of economising the use of labour outrunning the pace at which we can find new uses for labour. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; John Maynard Keynes,  the essay &#8220;Economic Possibilities for our Grandchildren&#8221;, 1930</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>the biological evolution of Homo sapiens was usurped by socio-cultural evolution</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/the-biological-evolution-of-homo-sapiens-was-usurped-by-socio-cultural-evolution.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-15-the-biological-evolution-of-homo-sapiens-was-usurped-by-socio-cultural-evolution.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-15T15:08:25Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-15T15:08:25Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Jürgen Klüver</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Many biologists and social scientists have noted that with the development of human culture, the biological evolution of Homo sapiens was usurped by socio-cultural evolution. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Many biologists and social scientists have noted that with the development of human culture, the biological evolution of Homo sapiens was usurped by socio-cultural evolution. The construction of artificial environments and social structures created new criteria for selection, and biological fitness was replaced by &#8216;cultural fitness&#8217;, which is often different for different cultures and is generally not measured by the number of offspring. Moreover, the mechanism of socio-cultural evolution is different from the model of biological evolution that was proposed by Charles Darwin (1809–1882), and refined by many others. In essence, socio-cultural evolution is &#8216;Lamarckian&#8217; in nature &#8211; it is an example of acquired inheritance, as described by the French naturalist Jean-Baptiste Lamarck (1744–1829) &#8211; because humans are able to pass on cultural achievements to the next generation. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Jürgen Klüver, 2008-07-09</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Dreams Come True</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/dreams-come-true.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-11-dreams-come-true.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-11T17:00:36Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-11T17:00:36Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>John Updike</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Dreams come true. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Dreams come true. Without that possibility, nature would not incite us to have them. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; John Updike, <cite>Self-Consciousness: Memoirs</cite>, 1989</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>We All Derive From the Same Source</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/we-all-derive-from-the-same-source.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-10-we-all-derive-from-the-same-source.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-10T14:55:08Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-10T14:55:08Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Henry Miller</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Every day we slaughter our finest impulses. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Every day we slaughter our finest impulses. That is why we get a heartache when we read those lines written by the hand of a master and recognize them as our own, as the tender shoots which we stifled because we lacked the faith to believe in our own powers, our own criterion of truth and beauty. Every man, when he gets quiet, when he becomes desperately honest with himself, is capable of uttering profound truths. We all derive from the same source. there is no mystery about the origin of things. We are all part of creation, all kings, all poets, all musicians; we have only to open up, only to discover what is already there. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Henry Miller,  the book <cite>Henry Miller on Writing</cite>, 1964</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>The Loftiest and Purest Art</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/the-loftiest-and-purest-art.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-09-the-loftiest-and-purest-art.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-09T14:32:56Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-09T14:32:56Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Walt Whitman</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Talk not so much, then, young artist, of the great old masters, who but painted and chisell&apos;d. Study not only their productions. There is a still higher school for him who would kindle his fire with coal from the altar of the loftiest and purest art. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Talk not so much, then, young artist, of the great old masters, who but painted and chisell&#8217;d. Study not only their productions. There is a still higher school for him who would kindle his fire with coal from the altar of the loftiest and purest art. It is the school of all grand actions and grand virtues, of heroism, of the death of patriots and martyrs &#8211; of all the mighty deeds written in the pages of history &#8211; deeds of daring, and enthusiasm, devotion, and fortitude. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Walt Whitman</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>A foolish consistency</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/a-foolish-consistency.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-08-a-foolish-consistency.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-08T16:48:41Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-08T16:48:41Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Ralph Waldo Emerson</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  A foolish consistency is the hobgoblin of little minds, adored by little statesmen and philosophers and divines&#8230;. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>A foolish consistency is the hobgoblin of little minds, adored by little statesmen and philosophers and divines. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Ralph Waldo Emerson,  the essay &#8220;Essential Writings of Ralph Waldo Emerson&#8221;, 1841</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>The Human Experiment is Now in Question</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/the-human-experiment-is-now-in-question.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-07-the-human-experiment-is-now-in-question.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-07T16:01:17Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-07T16:01:17Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Bill McKibben</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Put simply, between ecological destruction and technological hubris, the human experiment is now in question. The stakes feel very high, and the odds very long, and the trends very ominous. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Put simply, between ecological destruction and technological hubris, the human experiment is now in question. The stakes feel very high, and the odds very long, and the trends very ominous. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Bill McKibben,  the book <cite>Falter: Has the Human Game Begun to Play Itself Out?</cite>, 2019</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Your company’s purpose is its north star</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/your-companys-purpose-is-its-north-star.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-06-your-companys-purpose-is-its-north-star.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-06T17:15:53Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-06T17:15:53Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Larry Fink</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  It’s never been more essential for CEOs to have a consistent voice, a clear purpose, a coherent strategy, and a long-term view. Your company’s purpose is its north star in this tumultuous environment. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>It’s never been more essential for CEOs to have a consistent voice, a clear purpose, a coherent strategy, and a long-term view. Your company’s purpose is its north star in this tumultuous environment. Putting your company’s purpose at the foundation of your relationships with your stakeholders is critical to long-term success. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Larry Fink,  the letter &#8220;Letter to CEOs from Larry Fink in 2022&#8221;, 2022</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>The Eternal Struggle for Human Rights</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/the-eternal-struggle-for-human-rights.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-05-the-eternal-struggle-for-human-rights.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-05T15:40:30Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-05T15:40:30Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Albert Einstein</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  The existence and validity of human rights are not written in the stars. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>The existence and validity of human rights are not written in the stars. The ideals concerning the conduct of men toward each other and the desirable structure of the community have been conceived and taught by enlightened individuals in the course of history. Those ideals and convictions which resulted from historical experience, from the craving for beauty and harmony, have been readily accepted in theory by man &#8211; and at all times, have been trampled upon by the same people under the pressure of their animal instincts. A large part of history is therefore replete with the struggle for those human rights, an eternal struggle in which a final victory can never be won. But to tire in that struggle would mean the ruin of society. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Albert Einstein,  the speech &#8220;Address to the Chicago Decalogue Society&#8221;, 20 Feb 1954</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>No true patriot</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/no-true-patriot.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-04-no-true-patriot.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-04T18:37:33Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-04T18:37:33Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>G. K. Chesterton</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  &apos;My country, right or wrong,&apos; is a thing that no true patriot would think of saying. . . . 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>&#8216;My country, right or wrong,&#8217; is a thing that no true patriot would think of saying. . . . It is like saying, &#8216;My mother, drunk or sober&#8217;. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; G. K. Chesterton</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>The Divine Gift of Purely Nonsensical Speech and Action</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/the-divine-gift-of-purely-nonsensical-speech-and-action.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-03-the-divine-gift-of-purely-nonsensical-speech-and-action.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-03T17:04:50Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-03T17:04:50Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Edmund Crispin</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Fen sighed. &quot;We are all becoming standardized and normal, Nigel. The divine gift of purely nonsensical speech and action is in atrophy. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Fen sighed. &#8220;We are all becoming standardized and normal, Nigel. The divine gift of purely nonsensical speech and action is in atrophy. Would you believe it, a pupil of mine had the impertinence the other day to tick me off for reading him passages regarding the Fimble Fowl and the Quangle-Wangle as an illustration of pure poetic inventiveness; I put him in his place all right.&#8221; In the semi-darkness his eye became momentarily lambent with remembered satisfaction. &#8220;But there&#8217;s no eccentricity nowadays &#8211; none at all.&#8221; </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Edmund Crispin,  the book <cite>The Case of the Gilded Fly</cite>, 1944</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Our Reply to Violence</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/our-reply-to-violence.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-02-our-reply-to-violence.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-02T17:16:02Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-02T17:16:02Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Leonard Bernstein</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  This will be our reply to violence: to make music more intensely, more beautifully, more devotedly than ever before. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>This will be our reply to violence: to make music more intensely, more beautifully, more devotedly than ever before. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Leonard Bernstein</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Design is the fundamental soul of a man-made creation</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/design-is-the-fundamental-soul-of-a-man-made-creation.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-01-design-is-the-fundamental-soul-of-a-man-made-creation.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-01T20:34:38Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-01T20:34:38Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Steve Jobs</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  In most people&apos;s vocabularies, design means veneer. It&apos;s interior decorating. It&apos;s the fabric of the curtains and the sofa. But to me, nothing could be further from the meaning of design. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>In most people&#8217;s vocabularies, design means veneer. It&#8217;s interior decorating. It&#8217;s the fabric of the curtains and the sofa. But to me, nothing could be further from the meaning of design. Design is the fundamental soul of a man-made creation that ends up expressing itself in successive outer layers of the product or service. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Steve Jobs,  the interview &#8220;Apple's One-Dollar-a-Year Man&#8221;, January 24, 2000</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>The legitimate object of government</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/the-legitimate-object-of-government.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-30-the-legitimate-object-of-government.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-30T16:07:13Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-30T16:07:13Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Abraham Lincoln</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  The legitimate object of government, is to do for a community of people, whatever they need to have done, but can not do, at all, or can not, so well do, for themselves &#8211; in their separate, and individual capacities. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>The legitimate object of government, is to do for a community of people, whatever they need to have done, but can not do, at all, or can not, so well do, for themselves &#8211; in their separate, and individual capacities. In all that the people can individually do as well for themselves, government ought not to interfere. The desirable things which the individuals of a people can not do, or can not well do, for themselves, fall into two classes: those which have relation to wrongs, and those which have not. Each of these branch off into an infinite variety of subdivisions. The first &#8211; that in relation to wrongs &#8211; embraces all crimes, misdemeanors, and nonperformance of contracts. The other embraces all which, in its nature, and without wrong, requires combined action, as public roads and highways, public schools, charities, pauperism, orphanage, estates of the deceased, and the machinery of government itself. From this it appears that if all men were just, there still would be some, though not so much, need for government. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Abraham Lincoln,  the article &#8220;Fragment on Government&#8221;, 1854</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>The chicken experiment</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/the-chicken-experiment.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-29-the-chicken-experiment.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-29T17:59:42Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-29T17:59:42Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>David Sloan Wilson</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  But the chicken experiments suggest that this logic is flawed &#8211; even for farm animals where eugenics is a common practice. It seems Francis Galton was deeply mistaken about the relationship between individual abilities and societal welfare. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>But the chicken experiments suggest that this logic is flawed &#8211; even for farm animals where eugenics is a common practice. It seems Francis Galton was deeply mistaken about the relationship between individual abilities and societal welfare. The number of eggs laid by an individual hen is not an individual trait so much as it is a social trait, because it depends upon how members of the group behave towards each other. If the individuals who profit most from a social group do not contribute to the group&#8217;s welfare, and if their traits are heritable, then selecting for them results in the collapse of the society. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; David Sloan Wilson,  the interview &#8220;This View of Life: Completing the Darwinian Revolution&#8221;, 2019</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Relieving Ignorance</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/relieving-ignorance.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-26-relieving-ignorance.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-26T17:51:13Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-26T17:51:13Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Matthew Stewart</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  &quot;Customer satisfaction&quot; is a good way to sell shoes; but it is a bad way to relieve ignorance. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>&#8220;Customer satisfaction&#8221; is a good way to sell shoes; but it is a bad way to relieve ignorance. It is fundamentally stupid to base the content of an education on what the as-yet uneducated person decides is best. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Matthew Stewart,  the book <cite>The Management Myth: Why the Experts Keep Getting it Wrong</cite>, 2009</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>To end up here in a pile of bones</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/to-end-up-here-in-a-pile-of-bones.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-25-to-end-up-here-in-a-pile-of-bones.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-25T14:54:42Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-25T14:54:42Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Frank Capra</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Not until we showed them some of the stuff we got at Dachau, that George Stevens photographed with his crew, did it actually impinge itself on the mind of the horror, the horror of this whole thing.  Man, the highest of all the animals&#8230; 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Not until we showed them some of the stuff we got at Dachau, that George Stevens photographed with his crew, did it actually impinge itself on the mind of the horror, the horror of this whole thing.  Man, the highest of all the animals&#8230; the Man who created God&#8230; to end up here in a pile of bones, burned&#8230; it left me just speechless, colorless, bloodless. I couldn&#8217;t possibly believe that there was this kind of savagery in the world, you see. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Frank Capra,  the interview &#8220;Bill Moyers&#8221;, 1984</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Life is not like formula fiction</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/life-is-not-like-formula-fiction.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-24-life-is-not-like-formula-fiction.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-24T18:44:46Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-24T18:44:46Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Anne Lamott</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Life is not like formula fiction. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Life is not like formula fiction. The villain has a heart, and the hero has great flaws. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Anne Lamott,  the book <cite>Bird by Bird: Some Instructions on Writing and Life</cite>, 1994</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
</feed>
