<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Portable Wisdom</title>
  <subtitle>Daily Quotations from the desk of H. Bowie</subtitle>
  <link href="https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/feeds/atom.xml" type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://hbowie.net/" type="text/html" rel="alternate"  />
  <updated>2025-04-06T09:00:00Z</updated>
  <rights>Fair Use</rights>
  <author>
	<name>Various</name>
  </author>
  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/feeds/atom.xml</id>
	<entry>
	  <title>Your company’s purpose is its north star</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/your-companys-purpose-is-its-north-star.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-06-your-companys-purpose-is-its-north-star.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-06T17:15:53Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-06T17:15:53Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Larry Fink</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  It’s never been more essential for CEOs to have a consistent voice, a clear purpose, a coherent strategy, and a long-term view. Your company’s purpose is its north star in this tumultuous environment. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>It’s never been more essential for CEOs to have a consistent voice, a clear purpose, a coherent strategy, and a long-term view. Your company’s purpose is its north star in this tumultuous environment. Putting your company’s purpose at the foundation of your relationships with your stakeholders is critical to long-term success. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Larry Fink,  the letter &#8220;Letter to CEOs from Larry Fink in 2022&#8221;, 2022</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>The Eternal Struggle for Human Rights</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/the-eternal-struggle-for-human-rights.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-05-the-eternal-struggle-for-human-rights.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-05T15:40:30Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-05T15:40:30Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Albert Einstein</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  The existence and validity of human rights are not written in the stars. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>The existence and validity of human rights are not written in the stars. The ideals concerning the conduct of men toward each other and the desirable structure of the community have been conceived and taught by enlightened individuals in the course of history. Those ideals and convictions which resulted from historical experience, from the craving for beauty and harmony, have been readily accepted in theory by man &#8211; and at all times, have been trampled upon by the same people under the pressure of their animal instincts. A large part of history is therefore replete with the struggle for those human rights, an eternal struggle in which a final victory can never be won. But to tire in that struggle would mean the ruin of society. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Albert Einstein,  the speech &#8220;Address to the Chicago Decalogue Society&#8221;, 20 Feb 1954</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>No true patriot</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/no-true-patriot.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-04-no-true-patriot.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-04T18:37:33Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-04T18:37:33Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>G. K. Chesterton</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  &apos;My country, right or wrong,&apos; is a thing that no true patriot would think of saying. . . . 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>&#8216;My country, right or wrong,&#8217; is a thing that no true patriot would think of saying. . . . It is like saying, &#8216;My mother, drunk or sober&#8217;. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; G. K. Chesterton</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>The Divine Gift of Purely Nonsensical Speech and Action</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/the-divine-gift-of-purely-nonsensical-speech-and-action.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-03-the-divine-gift-of-purely-nonsensical-speech-and-action.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-03T17:04:50Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-03T17:04:50Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Edmund Crispin</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Fen sighed. &quot;We are all becoming standardized and normal, Nigel. The divine gift of purely nonsensical speech and action is in atrophy. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Fen sighed. &#8220;We are all becoming standardized and normal, Nigel. The divine gift of purely nonsensical speech and action is in atrophy. Would you believe it, a pupil of mine had the impertinence the other day to tick me off for reading him passages regarding the Fimble Fowl and the Quangle-Wangle as an illustration of pure poetic inventiveness; I put him in his place all right.&#8221; In the semi-darkness his eye became momentarily lambent with remembered satisfaction. &#8220;But there&#8217;s no eccentricity nowadays &#8211; none at all.&#8221; </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Edmund Crispin,  the book <cite>The Case of the Gilded Fly</cite>, 1944</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Our Reply to Violence</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/our-reply-to-violence.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-02-our-reply-to-violence.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-02T17:16:02Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-02T17:16:02Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Leonard Bernstein</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  This will be our reply to violence: to make music more intensely, more beautifully, more devotedly than ever before. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>This will be our reply to violence: to make music more intensely, more beautifully, more devotedly than ever before. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Leonard Bernstein</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Design is the fundamental soul of a man-made creation</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/design-is-the-fundamental-soul-of-a-man-made-creation.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-01-design-is-the-fundamental-soul-of-a-man-made-creation.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-01T20:34:38Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-01T20:34:38Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Steve Jobs</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  In most people&apos;s vocabularies, design means veneer. It&apos;s interior decorating. It&apos;s the fabric of the curtains and the sofa. But to me, nothing could be further from the meaning of design. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>In most people&#8217;s vocabularies, design means veneer. It&#8217;s interior decorating. It&#8217;s the fabric of the curtains and the sofa. But to me, nothing could be further from the meaning of design. Design is the fundamental soul of a man-made creation that ends up expressing itself in successive outer layers of the product or service. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Steve Jobs,  the interview &#8220;Apple's One-Dollar-a-Year Man&#8221;, January 24, 2000</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>The legitimate object of government</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/the-legitimate-object-of-government.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-30-the-legitimate-object-of-government.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-30T16:07:13Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-30T16:07:13Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Abraham Lincoln</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  The legitimate object of government, is to do for a community of people, whatever they need to have done, but can not do, at all, or can not, so well do, for themselves &#8211; in their separate, and individual capacities. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>The legitimate object of government, is to do for a community of people, whatever they need to have done, but can not do, at all, or can not, so well do, for themselves &#8211; in their separate, and individual capacities. In all that the people can individually do as well for themselves, government ought not to interfere. The desirable things which the individuals of a people can not do, or can not well do, for themselves, fall into two classes: those which have relation to wrongs, and those which have not. Each of these branch off into an infinite variety of subdivisions. The first &#8211; that in relation to wrongs &#8211; embraces all crimes, misdemeanors, and nonperformance of contracts. The other embraces all which, in its nature, and without wrong, requires combined action, as public roads and highways, public schools, charities, pauperism, orphanage, estates of the deceased, and the machinery of government itself. From this it appears that if all men were just, there still would be some, though not so much, need for government. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Abraham Lincoln,  the article &#8220;Fragment on Government&#8221;, 1854</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>The chicken experiment</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/the-chicken-experiment.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-29-the-chicken-experiment.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-29T17:59:42Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-29T17:59:42Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>David Sloan Wilson</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  But the chicken experiments suggest that this logic is flawed &#8211; even for farm animals where eugenics is a common practice. It seems Francis Galton was deeply mistaken about the relationship between individual abilities and societal welfare. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>But the chicken experiments suggest that this logic is flawed &#8211; even for farm animals where eugenics is a common practice. It seems Francis Galton was deeply mistaken about the relationship between individual abilities and societal welfare. The number of eggs laid by an individual hen is not an individual trait so much as it is a social trait, because it depends upon how members of the group behave towards each other. If the individuals who profit most from a social group do not contribute to the group&#8217;s welfare, and if their traits are heritable, then selecting for them results in the collapse of the society. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; David Sloan Wilson,  the interview &#8220;This View of Life: Completing the Darwinian Revolution&#8221;, 2019</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Relieving Ignorance</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/relieving-ignorance.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-26-relieving-ignorance.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-26T17:51:13Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-26T17:51:13Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Matthew Stewart</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  &quot;Customer satisfaction&quot; is a good way to sell shoes; but it is a bad way to relieve ignorance. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>&#8220;Customer satisfaction&#8221; is a good way to sell shoes; but it is a bad way to relieve ignorance. It is fundamentally stupid to base the content of an education on what the as-yet uneducated person decides is best. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Matthew Stewart,  the book <cite>The Management Myth: Why the Experts Keep Getting it Wrong</cite>, 2009</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>To end up here in a pile of bones</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/to-end-up-here-in-a-pile-of-bones.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-25-to-end-up-here-in-a-pile-of-bones.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-25T14:54:42Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-25T14:54:42Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Frank Capra</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Not until we showed them some of the stuff we got at Dachau, that George Stevens photographed with his crew, did it actually impinge itself on the mind of the horror, the horror of this whole thing.  Man, the highest of all the animals&#8230; 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Not until we showed them some of the stuff we got at Dachau, that George Stevens photographed with his crew, did it actually impinge itself on the mind of the horror, the horror of this whole thing.  Man, the highest of all the animals&#8230; the Man who created God&#8230; to end up here in a pile of bones, burned&#8230; it left me just speechless, colorless, bloodless. I couldn&#8217;t possibly believe that there was this kind of savagery in the world, you see. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Frank Capra,  the interview &#8220;Bill Moyers&#8221;, 1984</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Life is not like formula fiction</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/life-is-not-like-formula-fiction.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-24-life-is-not-like-formula-fiction.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-24T18:44:46Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-24T18:44:46Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Anne Lamott</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Life is not like formula fiction. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Life is not like formula fiction. The villain has a heart, and the hero has great flaws. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Anne Lamott,  the book <cite>Bird by Bird: Some Instructions on Writing and Life</cite>, 1994</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Three Layers of Tribal Instincts</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/three-layers-of-tribal-instincts.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-23-three-layers-of-tribal-instincts.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-23T15:41:13Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-23T15:41:13Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Michael Morris</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  In this book, I peel the onion of our special human talent for sharing with groups to distinguish three layers of “tribal instincts.” They originated in the Stone Age, but we can still recognize these evolved systems in our minds and hearts today. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>In this book, I peel the onion of our special human talent for sharing with groups to distinguish three layers of “tribal instincts.” They originated in the Stone Age, but we can still recognize these evolved systems in our minds and hearts today. Our sideways glances at classmates, coworkers, and neighbors are part of the <em>peer instinct</em>, as is our impulse to mesh with their patterns in our everyday inferences and actions. Our upward-directed fascination with celebrities, CEOs, MVPs, and other elites comes from the <em>hero instinct</em>, as do our aspirations for glory and our drive to contribute. Our backward-gazing nostalgia is part of the <em>ancestor instinct</em>, as is the comfort we find in traditions and the duty we feel to maintain them. These instincts are like three characters inside every person: the conformist who seeks belonging and understanding, the contributor who dreams of esteem and tribute, and the traditionalist who cherishes continuity. Each of these systems has its fallibilities, but—as we’ll see—each generally guides people in adaptive directions. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Michael Morris,  the book <cite>Tribal: How the Cultural Instincts That Divide Us Can Help Bring Us Together</cite>, 2024</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Imagination is not a means of making money</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/imagination-is-not-a-means-of-making-money.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-22-imagination-is-not-a-means-of-making-money.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-22T17:17:52Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-22T17:17:52Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Ursula K. Le Guin</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  In America the imagination is generally looked on as something that might be useful when the TV is out of order. Poetry and plays have no relation to practical politics. Novels are for students, housewives, and other people who don&apos;t work. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>In America the imagination is generally looked on as something that might be useful when the TV is out of order. Poetry and plays have no relation to practical politics. Novels are for students, housewives, and other people who don&#8217;t work. Fantasy is for children and primitive peoples. Literacy is so you can read the operating instructions. I think the imagination is the single most useful tool mankind possesses. It beats the opposable thumb. I can imagine living without my thumbs, but not without my imagination. </p>

<p>I hear voices agreeing with me. &#8220;Yes, yes!&#8221; they cry. &#8220;The creative imagination is a tremendous plus in business! We value creativity, we reward it!&#8221; In the marketplace, the word creativity has come to mean the generation of ideas applicable to practical strategies to make larger profits. This reduction has gone on so long that the word creative can hardly be degraded further. I don&#8217;t use it any more, yielding it to capitalists and academics to abuse as they like. But they can&#8217;t have imagination. </p>

<p>Imagination is not a means of making money. It has no place in the vocabulary of profit-making. It is not a weapon, though all weapons originate from it, and their use, or non-use, depends on it, as with all tools and their uses. The imagination is an essential tool of the mind, a fundamental way of thinking, an indispensable means of becoming and remaining human. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Ursula K. Le Guin,  the book <cite>Words Are My Matter</cite>, 2016</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Only Connect</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/only-connect.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-21-only-connect.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-21T14:43:05Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-21T14:43:05Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>E. M. Forster</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Only connect! That was the whole of her sermon. Only connect the prose and the passion and both will be exalted, and human love will be seen at its height. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Only connect! That was the whole of her sermon. Only connect the prose and the passion and both will be exalted, and human love will be seen at its height. Live in fragments no longer. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; E. M. Forster,  the book <cite>Howard”s End</cite>, 1910</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Workers demanding more from their employers</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/workers-demanding-more-from-their-employers.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-20-workers-demanding-more-from-their-employers.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-20T14:36:47Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-20T14:36:47Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Larry Fink</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Workers demanding more from their employers is an essential feature of effective capitalism. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Workers demanding more from their employers is an essential feature of effective capitalism. It drives prosperity and creates a more competitive landscape for talent, pushing companies to create better, more innovative environments for their employees – actions that will help them achieve greater profits for their shareholders. Companies that deliver are reaping the rewards. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Larry Fink,  the letter &#8220;Letter to CEOs from Larry Fink in 2022&#8221;, 2022</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>The Challenge of Swing</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/the-challenge-of-swing.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-19-the-challenge-of-swing.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-19T19:33:05Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-19T19:33:05Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Wynton Marsalis</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Swing — the dance and the music — bespeaks the flexible nature of American life. In jazz, the bass walks a note on every beat. The drummer rides the cymbal or plays brushes on every beat. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Swing — the dance and the music — bespeaks the flexible nature of American life. In jazz, the bass walks a note on every beat. The drummer rides the cymbal or plays brushes on every beat. And everybody else invents melodies and sounds that sway with, against, and upside every beat. Every beat requires musicians to reassess their relationships to one another. This is what makes swinging so challenging. You are forced to be constantly aware of other people&#8217;s feelings. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Wynton Marsalis,  the book <cite>Moving to Higher Ground: How Jazz Can Change Your Life</cite>, 2008</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Technological Unemployment</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/technological-unemployment.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-18-technological-unemployment.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-18T15:32:31Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-18T15:32:31Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>John Maynard Keynes</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  We are being afflicted with a new disease of which some readers may not yet have heard the name, but of which they will hear a great deal in the years to come &#8211; namely, technological unemployment. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>We are being afflicted with a new disease of which some readers may not yet have heard the name, but of which they will hear a great deal in the years to come &#8211; namely, technological unemployment. This means unemployment due to our discovery of means of economising the use of labour outrunning the pace at which we can find new uses for labour. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; John Maynard Keynes,  the essay &#8220;Economic Possibilities for our Grandchildren&#8221;, 1930</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Democracy is Worst Form of Government</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/democracy-is-worst-form-of-government.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-17-democracy-is-worst-form-of-government.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-17T18:31:46Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-17T18:31:46Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Winston Churchill</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Democracy is the worst form of government&#8230; 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Democracy is the worst form of government&#8230; except for all those others that have been tried. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Winston Churchill</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>You have your position because of the events of history</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/you-have-your-position-because-of-the-events-of-history.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-16-you-have-your-position-because-of-the-events-of-history.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-16T15:42:34Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-16T15:42:34Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Martin Luther King Jr.</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  No matter where you stand, no matter how much popularity you have, no matter how much education you have, no matter how much money you have, you have it because somebody in this universe helped you to get it. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>No matter where you stand, no matter how much popularity you have, no matter how much education you have, no matter how much money you have, you have it because somebody in this universe helped you to get it. And when you see that, you can&#8217;t be arrogant, you can&#8217;t be supercilious. You discover that you have your position because of the events of history and because of individuals in the background making it possible for you to stand there. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Martin Luther King Jr.,  the sermon &#8220;Conquering Self-centeredness&#8221;, 1957</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Finish every day and be done with it</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/finish-every-day-and-be-done-with-it.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-03-15-finish-every-day-and-be-done-with-it.html</id>
	  <published>2025-03-15T15:57:34Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-03-15T15:57:34Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Ralph Waldo Emerson</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Finish every day and be done with it. For manners and for wise living it is a vice to remember. You have done what you could; some blunders and absurdities no doubt crept in: forget them as fast as you can. Tomorrow is a new day. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Finish every day and be done with it. For manners and for wise living it is a vice to remember. You have done what you could; some blunders and absurdities no doubt crept in: forget them as fast as you can. Tomorrow is a new day. You shall begin it well and serenely, and with too high a spirit to be cumbered with your old nonsense. This day for all that is good and fair. It is too dear, with its hopes and invitations, to waste a moment on the rotten yesterdays. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Ralph Waldo Emerson,  the letter &#8220;To Daughter Ellen&#8221;, 8 Apr 1854</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
</feed>
