<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Portable Wisdom</title>
  <subtitle>Daily Quotations from the desk of H. Bowie</subtitle>
  <link href="https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/feeds/atom.xml" type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://hbowie.net/" type="text/html" rel="alternate"  />
  <updated>2026-02-07T09:00:00Z</updated>
  <rights>Fair Use</rights>
  <author>
	<name>Various</name>
  </author>
  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/feeds/atom.xml</id>
	<entry>
	  <title>Inextricably Linked in Freedom</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/inextricably-linked-in-freedom.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2026-02-07-inextricably-linked-in-freedom.html</id>
	  <published>2026-02-07T18:17:05Z</published>
	  <updated>2026-02-07T18:17:05Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Wynton Marsalis</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  The originators of jazz were only two generations removed from slavery. They were victims of rigorous forms of segregation that routinely and institutionally denied their humanity. So freedom was much more than a word to them. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>The originators of jazz were only two generations removed from slavery. They were victims of rigorous forms of segregation that routinely and institutionally denied their humanity. So freedom was much more than a word to them. These pioneering musicians were exuberant about exhibiting this newfound personal freedom through their art. But they were also excited about hearing other people do the same thing. They understood that all were inextricably linked in freedom, just as they had been inextricably linked in bondage. And it wasn&#8217;t theory; it was life as they lived it. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Wynton Marsalis, from  the book <cite>Moving to Higher Ground: How Jazz Can Change Your Life</cite>, 2008, &#x0a9; Wynton Marsalis Enterprises</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Rough consensus and running code</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/rough-consensus-and-running-code.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2026-01-15-rough-consensus-and-running-code.html</id>
	  <published>2026-01-15T20:30:35Z</published>
	  <updated>2026-01-15T20:30:35Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>David D. Clark</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  We reject: kings, presidents, and voting. We believe in: rough consensus and running code. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>We reject: kings, presidents, and voting. We believe in: rough consensus and running code. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; David D. Clark, from  the presentation &#8220;A Cloudy Crystal Ball -- Visions of the Future&#8221;, 1992, &#x0a9; David Clark</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>National parks and reserves</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/national-parks-and-reserves.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-09-10-national-parks-and-reserves.html</id>
	  <published>2025-09-10T16:31:38Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-09-10T16:31:38Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>John F. Kennedy</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  The supreme reality of our time is &#8230; the vulnerability of our planet. </p>

<p>National parks and reserves are an integral aspect of intelligent use of natural resources. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>The supreme reality of our time is &#8230; the vulnerability of our planet. </p>

<p>National parks and reserves are an integral aspect of intelligent use of natural resources. It is the course of wisdom to set aside an ample portion of our natural resources as national parks and reserves, thus ensuring that future generations may know the majesty of the earth as we know it today. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; John F. Kennedy</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>We may be the last generation in the experiment with living</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/we-may-be-the-last-generation-in-the-experiment-with-living.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-09-04-we-may-be-the-last-generation-in-the-experiment-with-living.html</id>
	  <published>2025-09-04T17:43:49Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-09-04T17:43:49Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Tom Hayden</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Our work is guided by the sense that we may be the last generation in the experiment with living. But we are a minority &#8211; the vast majority of our people regard the temporary equilibriums of our society and world as eternally functional parts. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Our work is guided by the sense that we may be the last generation in the experiment with living. But we are a minority &#8211; the vast majority of our people regard the temporary equilibriums of our society and world as eternally functional parts. In this is perhaps the outstanding paradox; we ourselves are imbued with urgency, yet the message of our society is that there is no viable alternative to the present. Beneath the reassuring tones of the politicians, beneath the common opinion that America will &#8220;muddle through,&#8221; beneath the stagnation of those who have closed their minds to the future, is the pervading feeling that there simply are no alternatives, that our times have witnessed the exhaustion not only of Utopias, but of any new departures as well. Feeling the press of complexity upon the emptiness of life, people are fearful of the thought that at any moment things might be thrust out of control. They fear change itself, since change might smash whatever invisible framework seems to hold back chaos for them now. For most Americans, all crusades are suspect, threatening. The fact that each individual sees apathy in his fellows perpetuates the common reluctance to organize for change. The dominant institutions are complex enough to blunt the minds of their potential critics, and entrenched enough to swiftly dissipate or entirely repel the energies of protest and reform, thus limiting human expectancies. Then, too, we are a materially improved society, and by our own improvements we seem to have weakened the case for further change. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Tom Hayden, from  the paper &#8220;The Port Huron Statement&#8221;, 1962</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Your company’s purpose is its north star</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/your-companys-purpose-is-its-north-star.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-09-03-your-companys-purpose-is-its-north-star.html</id>
	  <published>2025-09-03T16:52:42Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-09-03T16:52:42Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Larry Fink</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  It’s never been more essential for CEOs to have a consistent voice, a clear purpose, a coherent strategy, and a long-term view. Your company’s purpose is its north star in this tumultuous environment. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>It’s never been more essential for CEOs to have a consistent voice, a clear purpose, a coherent strategy, and a long-term view. Your company’s purpose is its north star in this tumultuous environment. Putting your company’s purpose at the foundation of your relationships with your stakeholders is critical to long-term success. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Larry Fink, from  the letter &#8220;Letter to CEOs from Larry Fink in 2022&#8221;, 2022</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>The Change Dilemma</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/the-change-dilemma.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-08-31-the-change-dilemma.html</id>
	  <published>2025-08-31T16:41:04Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-08-31T16:41:04Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Sydney Harris</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Our dilemma is that we hate change and love it at the same time; what we really want is for things to remain the same but get better. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Our dilemma is that we hate change and love it at the same time; what we really want is for things to remain the same but get better. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Sydney Harris, 1999</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Easy Solutions</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/easy-solutions.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-08-27-easy-solutions.html</id>
	  <published>2025-08-27T23:01:10Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-08-27T23:01:10Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>H. L. Mencken</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  There is always an easy solution to every human problem &#8211; neat, plausible and wrong. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>There is always an easy solution to every human problem &#8211; neat, plausible and wrong. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; H. L. Mencken, from <cite>Prejudices: Second Series</cite>, 1920</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>The Third Place</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/the-third-place.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-05-15-the-third-place.html</id>
	  <published>2025-05-15T15:46:16Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-05-15T15:46:16Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Ray Oldenburg</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Most needed are those &apos;third places&apos; which lend a public balance to the increased privatization of home life. Third places are nothing more than informal public gathering places. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Most needed are those &#8216;third places&#8217; which lend a public balance to the increased privatization of home life. Third places are nothing more than informal public gathering places. The phrase &#8216;third places&#8217; derives from considering our homes to be the &#8216;first&#8217; places in our lives, and our work places the &#8216;second.&#8217; </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Ray Oldenburg, from  the book <cite>The Great Good Place</cite>, 1989, &#x0a9; Ray Oldenburg</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>To live wisely and agreeably and well</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/to-live-wisely-and-agreeably-and-well.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-05-14-to-live-wisely-and-agreeably-and-well.html</id>
	  <published>2025-05-14T14:54:02Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-05-14T14:54:02Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>John Maynard Keynes</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Thus for the first time since his creation man will be faced with his real, his permanent problem &#8211; how to use his freedom from pressing economic cares, how to occupy the leisure, which science and compound interest will have won for him, to live&#8230; 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Thus for the first time since his creation man will be faced with his real, his permanent problem &#8211; how to use his freedom from pressing economic cares, how to occupy the leisure, which science and compound interest will have won for him, to live wisely and agreeably and well. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; John Maynard Keynes, from  the essay &#8220;Economic Possibilities for our Grandchildren&#8221;, 1930</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>We are Doing our Best</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/we-are-doing-our-best.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-05-12-we-are-doing-our-best.html</id>
	  <published>2025-05-12T16:34:43Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-05-12T16:34:43Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Winston Churchill</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  It&apos;s no use saying, &apos;We are doing our best.&apos; You have got to succeed in doing what is necessary. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>It&#8217;s no use saying, &#8216;We are doing our best.&#8217; You have got to succeed in doing what is necessary. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Winston Churchill</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>A strange magic in human-made things</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/a-strange-magic-in-human-made-things.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-05-06-a-strange-magic-in-human-made-things.html</id>
	  <published>2025-05-06T18:51:32Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-05-06T18:51:32Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>J. K. Rowling</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  There can be a strange magic in human-made things. Not in all of them: not in plastic bottles or Q-Tips or batteries; but in those that are interwoven with our pasts, with our homes, with our great loves. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>There can be a strange magic in human-made things. Not in all of them: not in plastic bottles or Q-Tips or batteries; but in those that are interwoven with our pasts, with our homes, with our great loves. These are things that have been mysteriously imbued with humanity — our own or other people’s. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; J. K. Rowling, from  the article &#8220;J. K. Rowling on the Magic of 'Things'&#8221;, 24 Dec 2021</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Levels of Development</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/levels-of-development.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-05-05-levels-of-development.html</id>
	  <published>2025-05-05T17:28:13Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-05-05T17:28:13Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Ken Wilber</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  To grasp what is involved with levels or stages, let&apos;s use a very simple model possessing only 3 of them. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>To grasp what is involved with levels or stages, let&#8217;s use a very simple model possessing only 3 of them. If we look at moral development, for example, we find that an infant at birth has not yet been socialized into the culture&#8217;s ethics and conventions: this is called the <strong>preconventional stage</strong>. It is also called <strong>egocentric</strong>, in that the infant&#8217;s awareness is largely self-absorbed. But as the young child begins to learns its culture&#8217;s rules and norms, it grows into the <strong>conventional stage</strong> of morals. This stage is also called <strong>ethnocentric</strong>, in that it centers on the child&#8217;s particular group, tribe, clan, or nation, and it therefore tends to exclude those not of its group. But at the next major stage of moral development, the <strong>postconventional stage</strong>, the individual&#8217;s identity expands once again, this time to include a care and concern for all peoples, regardless of race, color, sex or creed, which is why this stage is also called <strong>worldcentric</strong>. </p>

<p>Thus, moral development tends to move from &#8216;me&#8217; (egocentric) to &#8216;us&#8217; (ethnocentric) to &#8216;all of us&#8217; (worldcentric)&#8211;a good example of the unfolding waves of consciousness. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Ken Wilber, from  the book <cite>the integral vision</cite>, 2007, &#x0a9; Ken Wilber</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Learning from Experience</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/learning-from-experience.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-05-03-learning-from-experience.html</id>
	  <published>2025-05-03T22:18:25Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-05-03T22:18:25Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Peter Senge</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  The most powerful learning comes from direct experience. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>The most powerful learning comes from direct experience. But what happens when we can no longer observe the consequences of our actions? Herein lies the core <em>learning dilemma</em> that confronts organizations:<em> we learn best from experience but we never directly experience the consequences of many of our most important decisions.</em> The most critical decisions made in organizations have systemwide consequences that stretch over years or decades. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Peter Senge, from  the book <cite>The Fifth Discipline: The Art and Practice of the Learning Organization</cite>, 1990, &#x0a9; Peter M. Senge.</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Those who tolerate or encourage evil</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/those-who-tolerate-or-encourage-evil.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-05-02-those-who-tolerate-or-encourage-evil.html</id>
	  <published>2025-05-02T20:47:54Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-05-02T20:47:54Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Albert Einstein</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  The world is in greater peril from those who tolerate or encourage evil than from those who actually commit it. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>The world is in greater peril from those who tolerate or encourage evil than from those who actually commit it. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Albert Einstein, from  the book <cite>Tribute to Pablo Casals</cite>, 30 Mar 1953</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>The heart of liberty</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/the-heart-of-liberty.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-30-the-heart-of-liberty.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-30T16:15:28Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-30T16:15:28Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Anthony M. Kennedy</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  At the heart of liberty is the right to define one’s own concept of existence, of meaning, of the universe, and of the mystery of human life. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>At the heart of liberty is the right to define one’s own concept of existence, of meaning, of the universe, and of the mystery of human life. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Anthony M. Kennedy, from  the opinion &#8220;Planned Parenthood v. Casey US Supreme Court opinion&#8221;, 1992</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Worshipping the divine right of capital</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/worshipping-the-divine-right-of-capital.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-29-worshipping-the-divine-right-of-capital.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-30T00:14:21Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-30T00:14:21Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Tim O'Reilly</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  Future economic historians may look back wryly at this period when we worshipped the divine right of capital while looking down on our ancestors who believed in the divine right of kings. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>Future economic historians may look back wryly at this period when we worshipped the divine right of capital while looking down on our ancestors who believed in the divine right of kings. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Tim O'Reilly, from  the book <cite>WTF: What's the Future and Why It's Up To Us</cite>, 1968, &#x0a9; Timothy F. O'Reilly</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>You can&apos;t dance cheerfully</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/you-cant-dance-cheerfully.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-28-you-cant-dance-cheerfully.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-28T17:41:41Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-28T17:41:41Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Rex Stout</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  As a dancing partner Rose Tuttle was not a bargain. She was equipped for it physically and she had some idea of rhythm, that wasn&apos;t it; it was her basic attitude. She danced cheerfully, and of course that was no good. You can&apos;t dance cheerfully. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>As a dancing partner Rose Tuttle was not a bargain. She was equipped for it physically and she had some idea of rhythm, that wasn&#8217;t it; it was her basic attitude. She danced cheerfully, and of course that was no good. You can&#8217;t dance cheerfully. Dancing is too important. It can be wild or solemn or gay or lewd or art for art&#8217;s sake, but it can&#8217;t be cheerful. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Rex Stout, from <cite>Champagne for One</cite>, 1958</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>These principles have no objective validity</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/these-principles-have-no-objective-validity.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-27-these-principles-have-no-objective-validity.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-27T17:16:38Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-27T17:16:38Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Yuval Noah Harari</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  The two texts present us with an obvious dilemma. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>The two texts present us with an obvious dilemma. Both the Code of Hammurabi and the American Declaration of Independence claim to outline universal and eternal principles of justice, but according to the Americans all people are equal, whereas according to the Babylonians people are decidedly unequal. The Americans would, of course, say that they are right, and that Hammurabi is wrong. Hammurabi, naturally, would retort that he is right, and that the Americans are wrong. In fact, they are both Wrong. Hammurabi and the American Founding Fathers alike imagined a reality governed by universal and immutable principles of justice, such as equality or hierarchy. Yet the only place where such universal principles exist is in the fertile imagination of Sapiens, and in the myths they invent and tell one another. These principles have no objective validity. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Yuval Noah Harari, from  the book <cite>Sapiens: A Brief History of Humankind</cite>, 2015, &#x0a9; Yuval Noah Harari</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>A Happy Man</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/a-happy-man.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-26-a-happy-man.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-26T14:37:48Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-26T14:37:48Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Albert Einstein</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  A happy man is too satisfied with the present to dwell too much on the future. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>A happy man is too satisfied with the present to dwell too much on the future. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Albert Einstein, from <cite>The Collected Papers of Albert Einstein</cite>, 18 September 1896</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
	<entry>
	  <title>Nature transcends our tendencies to label and classify</title>
	  <link rel="related" type="text/html" href="https://hbowie.net/quotes/nature-transcends-our-tendencies-to-label-and-classify.html"/>
	  <id>https://hbowie.net/portablewisdom/2025-04-25-nature-transcends-our-tendencies-to-label-and-classify.html</id>
	  <published>2025-04-25T14:34:35Z</published>
	  <updated>2025-04-25T14:34:35Z</updated>
	  <author>
		<name>Rick Rubin</name>
	  </author>
	  <summary>
		  If you&apos;re picking colors based on a Pantone book, you&apos;re limited to a certain number of choices. If you step out in nature, the palette is infinite. 
	  </summary>
	  <content type="xhtml">
	  	<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
		  <p>If you&#8217;re picking colors based on a Pantone book, you&#8217;re limited to a certain number of choices. If you step out in nature, the palette is infinite. Each rock has such a variation of color within it, we could never find a can of paint to mimic the exact same shade. </p>

<p>Nature transcends our tendencies to label and classify, to reduce and limit. The natural world is unfathomably more rich, interwoven, and complicated than we are taught, and so much more mysterious and beautiful. </p>
		  <p>&#8211; Rick Rubin, from  the book <cite>The Creative Act: A Way of Being</cite>, 2023</p>
		</div>
	  </content>
	</entry>
</feed>
